Guide to the Program in Judaic Studies, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Program in Judaic Studies, Yale University, records
1984-1999
RU 978
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
11.5
(10 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, and newsletters of the Program in Judaic Studies at Yale University. Topics include faculty, courses and seminars, lectures, search committees, and the Yale Judaica Series.
Yale University. Program in Judaic Studies
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Program in Judaic Studies, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
The Program in Judaic Studies (formerly the Judaic Studies Program at Yale) offers an interdisciplinary approach to undergraduate and graduate study of the religion, history, literature, languages, and material culture of the Jews from ancient to modern times.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, and newsletters of the Program in Judaic Studies at Yale University. Topics include faculty, courses and seminars, lectures, search committees, and the Yale Judaica Series.
Jews -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Program in Judaic Studies
- Correspondence, subject files, and newsletters of the Program in Judaic Studies, 1984-1999; Accession 2005-A-130
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2034
  - J. I. Judaic Studies (Box 1)
    - University Comm on Judaic Studies (Box 1)
  - Judaic Studies Majors
    - Senior Essay Forms (Box 1)
    - Senior Essays (Box 1)
  - Correspondence with Linda Lorimer
    - 1984 - 1985 (Box 1)
    - 1985 - 1986 (Box 1)
  - Yale Judaica Series (Box 1)
  - Judaic Advisory Committee (Box 1)
  - Faculty Review (Box 1)
  - Library Judaica Collection (Box 1)
  - JS Senior Essays (Box 1)
  - Judaic Studies
    - Campaign (Box 1)
    - Interdisciplinary Major (Box 1)
    - Provost (Box 1)
    - Campaign Development (Box 1)
    - Classical (Box 1)
    - Other candidates (Box 1)
    - Biblical (Box 1)
    - Medieval/ Renaissance (Box 1)
  - Hebrew Languages and Literature
    - Modern (Box 1)
    - Fine Arts (Box 1)
  - Judaic Studies Brochures
    - Sample Brochures, 1984 - 1985 (Box 1)
    - Copy, 1984 - 1985 (Box 1)
  - Judaic Studies Newsletter
    - Judaic Studies Newsletter (Box 1)
    - JS Newsletter, Winter 1984 (Box 1)
  - Rose Chair Applicants
    - Rose Chair Interviews (Box 2)
  - Hebrew Language and Literature Search, 1984 - 1985 (Box 2)
  - Search material for Lorimer (Box 2)
  - Hebrew Search file
    - Hebrew Language and Literature Search (Box 2)
  - Hebrew Literature Search Committee (Box 2)
  - Job opportunities (Box 2)
  - Modern Jewish History Search Short List
    - MJH Search Committee -applicants not in the running (Box 2)
  - Search Committees
    Restricted to Office of Origin only
    - Other search committees (Box 2)
    - MJH Search Committee -blind letter (Box 2)
    - ModJewHis -Search for candidates ads, letters to distinguished scholars etc. (Box 2)
    - Applications for chair in Modern Jewish History (Box 2)
    - Hebrew language and literature search committee (Box 2)
  - Paula Hyman Articles
    - Modern Jewish history search committee -responses of distinguished scholars (Box 2)
  - Advisory Committee -Judaic studies minutes
    - Yale Bulletin and calendar for Judaic studies majors (Box 2)
  - Senir Essay: Judaic Studies (Box 2)
  - From J.S. Development Office, New York (Box 2)
  - Visiting Faculty, Judaic Studies Program, 1984 - 1985
    - Faculty, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
    - Jr. Bible candidates (Box 3)
  - Judaic Studies Program -course statistics (Box 3)
  - Gifts to Judaic Studies, 1984- 1985 (Box 3)
  - Judaic Studies Indentures (Box 3)
  - Gifts to Judaic Studies, 1985 - 1986 (Box 3)
  - Links Fellowship, 1984 - 1985 (Box 3)
  - Visiting Professors, 1989-1990
    - Notice on visiting appointments, 1989 - 1990 (Box 3)
    - Applicants for visiting professors, 1989 - 1990 (Box 3)
  - Articles that appeared in newspapers (Box 3)
  - Visiting Professors, 1988-1989
    - Visiting Professors in Judaic Studies (Box 3)
    - Oliver W. Holmes (Box 3)
  - Visiting Professors, 1987-1988
    - Visiting Professors 1987 - 88 (Box 3)
  - Judaic studies visiting faculty, 1986-1987
    - Visiting Prof. Judaic Studies 1986 - 87 (Box 3)
  - Applications (Box 3)
  - Provost (Box 3)
  - Publicity - 1962 (Box 3)
  - Beginnings (Box 3)
  - Judaica Report for meeting on Dec 4, 1957 (Box 3)
  - NEH 1982 -1984 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Committee (Box 3)
  - Search Committee for position in Judaism in late Antiquity (Box 4)
  - Leander Keck, Dean of Divinity School (Box 4)
  - Dean/ Sidney Altman correspondence (Box 4)
  - Library Matters - Curatorship (Box 4)
  - Library Position (1988) (Box 4)
  - Hebrew Bible (Box 4)
  - Visitors, 1991-1992 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence regarding visitors, 1992 - 1992 (Box 4)
  - Yale Judaica Series
  - Yale Judaica Series
    - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Yale Judaica Series Authors
    - Yale Judaica Series (Box 4)
    - Judaica Series -NEH Grant (Box 4)
  - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Conference Call Information (Box 4)
  - Judaica Series Publications Committee (Box 4)
  - Contracts (completed or canceled) (Box 4)
  - Treasurer's office (Box 4)
  - Y J Series Meetings, 1991 May 22 (Box 4)
  - Y J Series Meetings, 1989 May 12 (Box 4)
  - Readers' reports (Box 4)
  - Possible donors for Judaica Series (Box 4)
  - Lectures -Spring 1999
    - Colloquium, 22 Apr (Box 5)
  - Faculty Graduate student seminars, 1998-1999
    - 24 March (Box 5)
  - Lectures Fall 1998
  - Lectures, 1998-1999
    - Legacies Conference Nov 1-3, 1997 (Box 5)
    - Judaic Studies Program Colloquium (Box 5)
    - J.S. Informational meeting, 23 Apr 1998 (Box 5)
  - Lectures, 1996-1997
  - Lectures, 1995-1996
  - Lectures, 1994-1995
    - Bauer, 16 Nov 1994 (Box 5)
  - Yale Judaica Series (Box 5)
  - Correspondence - grant (Box 5)
  - Occasional letters (Box 5)
  - Bargebuhr (Box 5)
  - Bowman (Box 5)
  - Braude (Box 5)
- Records, 1985-2007; Accession 2009-A-127
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2083.
  - Annual Reports -an annual description of all activities, 1987-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Grades
    - 1987-1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fellowships [restricted 75 years from date individual left Yale]
  - Undergrads. individual students -academic achievements, grades, 1989 - 1997 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Undergraduate student statistics -honors, grades, listing of majors, 1988 - 1997 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Postdoc positions [restricted 75 years from date individual left Yale]
  - Faculty/graduate student seminar, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Lectures
  - American Jewish Congress Prize and Obernauer Prize -description and winners, 1987-2000 (Box 4, Folder 223 - 226)
  - A guide to conducting faculty searches: appointments, reappointments, promotions, processing leaves and terminations., 1999-2001 (Box 4, Folder 227)
  - Senior Essays, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 228)
  - Prize Fellowships -Nominations Letter, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 229)
  - Course enrollment/procedures for making reaching appointments, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 230)
  - Teaching Assistant appointments, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 231)
  - Teaching Assistant appointments and procedures for making teaching appointments, 2001-2003 (Box 4, Folder 232)
  - Teaching Assistant Assignments, appointment descriptions, and student credentials, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 233)
  - Advisory Committee Meeting
    - New Appointments, visiting professor, course listing, congress prize winners, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 234)
    - Committee meetings, courses, visiting professors, Congress prize, Obernauer prize, 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 235)
    - Visiting faculty and course listings, 2003-2005 (Box 4, Folder 236)
  - Visiting Professors' Projected Budget
    - 2000-2002 (Box 4, Folder 237)
    - 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 238)
    - 1993-1999 (Box 4, Folder 239)
    - 1986-1993 (Box 4, Folder 240)
    - 2003-2005 (Box 4, Folder 241)
    - 2002-2004 (Box 4, Folder 242)
    - 2001-2003 (Box 4, Folder 243)
  - Revised Budget for visiting professors, 1999-2001 (Box 4, Folder 244)
  - Course Enrollments
    - Fall 2004 (Box 4, Folder 245)
    - Spring 2004 (Box 4, Folder 246)
    - Fall 2003 (Box 4, Folder 247)
    - Spring 2003 (Box 4, Folder 248)
    - Fall 2002 (Box 4, Folder 249)
    - Spring 2002 (Box 4, Folder 250)
    - Fall 2000 (Box 4, Folder 251)
    - Spring 2000 (Box 4, Folder 252)
    - Fall 2001 (Box 4, Folder 253)
    - Spring 2002 (Box 4, Folder 254)
    - Fall 1999 (Box 4, Folder 255)
    - Spring 1999 (Box 4, Folder 256)
    - Fall 1998 (Box 4, Folder 257)
    - Spring 1998 (Box 4, Folder 258)
  - Course Offerings
    - 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 259)
    - 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 260)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 261)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 262)
    - 1996-1999 (Box 4, Folder 263)
  - Provost's Office -minimum salary, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 268)